跟我说说你今天干了什么吧
So, tell me about your day--
粒子探测器的进展如何
how's it going with the particle detector?
哇  你还记着这个
Wow! You remember that?
当然  你的话我都有好好听
Yeah, I listen to what you say.
你正在用超流氦
You're building a particle detector
打造一个粒子探测器
using superfluid helium.
你说这些的时候
You know, when you talk like that,
我真想立马把你按倒在这餐桌上
I want to take you right here on this table.
根据以往的经验
And you know from past experience
这张桌子可承受不起我俩的重量
this table cannot support both our weight.
所以你那探测器做得怎么样了
So, how's the detector going?
超流体这玩意还挺难搞
Well, it's tricky working with superfluids.
不管放进什么容器里
Whatever container you put them in,
它都会从边上渗出来
they kind of creep up the sides
慢慢逃逸掉
and crawl out all on their own.
有点像谢尔顿的蚂蚁农场
Kind of like Sheldon's ant farm.
完全正确  只是这次不会有个疯子在旁边
Exactly, except you don't have a lunatic running around,
边跳边喊  我喂了你们糖水喝  为毛要咬我
yelling, "I fed you sugar water, why are you biting me?"
这太无聊了  你不会真想谈这个吧
Come on, this is boring-- you really want to talk about this?
我真的想听
No, I do.
我特意把超流氦写在
I-I didn't write "superfluid helium"
餐巾纸上可不是白费的
on this napkin for nothing.
好吧
Okay, well...
有个想法挺有趣的
This is cool.
有一种理论叫超流体真空论
Uh, there's a thing called "superfluid vacuum theory",
它把时空本身设定为是一个具有各种特质的
where empty space is imagined as a superfluid
液态超流体
with all of its qualities--
粘度  密度  表面张力
viscosity, density, surface tension...
如果你暂停是为了戏剧效果
Hey, if you're pausing for dramatic effect,
你还是继续说吧
I'd keep it moving.
不
No, no.
其他人都没提到  表面张力
People don't talk about surface tension.
如果你把三维空间想象为
If you imagine our three-space as the surface
一个N维空间的超流体气泡的表面
of an N-dimensional superfluid bubble...
这个...这个想法太有趣了
This... is exciting.
真的很有意思
This is really exciting.
我得去找谢尔顿了
I have to go find Sheldon.
如果你找到他
Okay, well, if you find him,
记得按倒到在厨房的岛台上...
use the kitchen island--
咖啡桌可承受不起你俩的重量
that coffee table will not support both of you.
所以球性多维超流体
Which means a spherical multidimensional superfluid
和时空具有同样的负能量密度
shows the same negative-energy density as space-time.
你觉得如何  如何如何  你觉得如何
So what do you think? What do you think? So what do you think?
怎么了  我错了吗
What? Is it wrong?
还是你已经看过这种理论了
Have you seen it somewhere else?
我知道这不是我的领域
I know this isn't my area,
我的数学也没你强
and I could never do the math like you can,
但这想法靠谱吗
but could this be something...?
这个嘛
Well...
你可以把牛顿的万有引力常数设为1
You could have set Newton's gravitational constant to one.
而且  到处都弥漫着一股蓝莓味
And, ugh, the whole thing reeks of blueberry.
我真是受不了这些香味记号笔
You know I can't stand these scented markers.
又没人叫你吃它们
No one told you to taste them.
这个想法到底好不好嘛
Come on, is-is this good or not?
很不错
It's good.
-真的吗  -我很看好它
- Really? - I like it.
我觉得这可能是个大发现
I think you're on to something.
真的吗  你没有逗我吧
You do? You're not messing with me?
完全没有
Not at all.
事实上  我为这种时刻
In fact, I have got something
专门准备了一个东西
for just such an occasion.
我还以为自己
I was starting to think
不会有机会把这个给你了呢
I might never get a chance to give it to you.
表现不错
Good job.
你给了我一张贴纸
You're giving me a sticker?
是的
Indeed.
但远不止贴纸那么简单
Not just a sticker.
贴纸上有只猫在说  干得喵
That is a sticker of a kitty saying, "Me-wow!"
我又不是幼儿园小孩儿
I'm not a preschooler.
那我把它收回吧
Fine, I'll take it back.
这是我应得的  别想拿走
I earned this! Back off!
你还没睡啊
You're still awake?
身为一个刚刚发现
For a man whose last observation was
宇宙时空可能是
our universe may be the surface
一个多维超冷液体的表面的人
of a multidimensional supercooled liquid,
"你还没睡啊"是小学二年级才会问的问题
"You're still awake" seems like quite the sophomore slump.
你完成了所有的计算
You worked out all the math.
我做的可不止计算
Oh, I did more than work out all the math.
我写了一篇论文
I wrote a paper.
你用我的想法写了一篇论文吗
You wrote a paper on my idea?
我用我们的想法写了一篇论文
I wrote a paper on our idea.
我的想法什么时候成了我们的想法
When did my idea become our idea?
当我在其中糅合了谢尔顿的精华
When I mixed it with Sheldony goodness
并用我的思维烤箱烘焙而成后
and cooked it in the Easy-Bake Oven of my mind.
写得真不错
This is good.
我们的想法真得很不错
Our idea is really good.
人家烤箱里面的小灯泡可以亮瞎你的眼呢
Well, the lightbulb in this oven is ridiculously bright.
如果这个想法没有人提出过
You know, if no one's thought of this, yet,
这绝对是个大发现啊
this could be a big deal.
检验的唯一方法就是
Only way we'll know for sure is
把它放到预发表服务器上去
if we post it online to the pre-print server.
我已经准备发了  但我要等你一起来
I have it ready to go, but I wasn't gonna do it without you.
这一切发生得太快了
Wow, it's all happening so fast.
我们要不要等明天再说啊
Should we just sleep on it?
可以  但也许其他人
We could, but we always run the risk
就会抢在我们前面了
of someone else beating us to the punch.
你确定这个想法靠谱吗
You're sure it's good?
我的名字就在你旁边
My name is right on there with yours.
这就是金牌品质保证
That is a surefire mark of quality.
这就好比由乔斯·威登执导的电影
That might as well say "Directed by Joss Whedon".
好吧  搭档  就这么干吧
Okay, partner, let's do it.
来
Come on.
和我一起按下鼠标吧
Click the mouse with me.
One...
two...
three...
点击
Click.
好了  我们真的做了
Well, we did it.
是的  我的朋友
Yes, we did, my friend.
你的舌头怎么是蓝色的
Is your tongue blue?
我不想谈这件事
I don't want to talk about it.
电影之夜  你们想看什么
Okay, movie night-- what do you want to watch?
你出演的那部猿人电影怎么样了
Whatever happened to that ape movie you were in?
天啊
Oh, God.
可能根本没发行
Probably nothing.
我好像看到导演在手机通讯行外面转广告牌呢
I think I saw the director twirling a sign outside the Verizon store.
搜搜看
Search for it.
什么  不  为什么啊
Wha... no. No! Why?
因为一定很好玩
'Cause it would be fun to watch.
我一定会丢脸死
It would be humiliating.
现在我们有两个理由了
Well, now we have two reasons.
上面有这部
They have it.
求求你了  让我们看吧
Please, can we watch it?
拜托了
Please?
好吧  不过我警告你们  超级难看
Fine, but I'm telling you-- it's terrible.
-你自己看过吗  -没有
- Have you even seen it? - No.
也许比你想得好多了
Well, maybe it turned out better than you think.
香蕉  新鲜的大香蕉
Bananas, get your fresh bananas.
看来是烂透了
It really didn't.
谢尔顿  这是超流氦
Sheldon, this is superfluid helium.
把这个放到嘴巴里
Put this in your mouth,
你的舌头就会冻成碎片
your tongue will freeze and break off.
它闻起来像蓝莓吗
Does it smell like blueberries?
不像
No.
那就应该没问题了
Then we're probably okay.
你们的论文被
Hey, your paper got mentioned
量子物理学博客提到了
on the Quantum Diaries physics blog.
真的吗
Really?
他们怎么说
Wh-What'd they say?
只是简单地介绍了一下这个理论
Uh, it's basically a summary of the theory,
不过下面有好多正面留言
but there's a bunch of positive comments on the message board.
让我看看  让我看看
Let me see, let me see.
有人称它是"有见地和非常创新"
One calls it "Insightful and innovative".
我们有见地  还非常创新
We're insightful and innovative.
你好  有见地先生
Ooh, nice to meet you, Mr. Insightful.
你好  非常创新先生
Oh, the pleasure is mine, Mr. Innovative.
还有人说  "这个理论显示出了
Uh, another one says, "The concept shows
极度发散的思维"
some real out-of-the-box thinking".
你听到了吗  发散先生
Do you hear that, Mr. Out-Of-The?
听到了  思维先生
dort dort dort I do, indeed, Mr. Box-Thinking.
你今天好吗
How are you today,
"这俩傻逼让人无语"先生
word word word Mr. Can-You-Believe-These-Jack-Asses?
挺好的
Just dandy, Mr....
"我要是更会胡扯就好了"先生
ppt ppt ppt ppt ppt I-Wish-I-Was-Better-At-Improv.
-再读一条  -好的
Read another one. Okay, okay. Uh...
"将时空与超冷液体
"The analogy between space-time
进行类比  要么没意义  要么是错的
and a supercooled fluid is either meaningless or... false".
我希望这个博客能关注真正的科学
"I wish this blog would devote itself to real science
而不是为了急于发表成果的
Instead of wasting our time with crackpot,
妄想成名的疯子理论家  浪费我们的时间"
wannabe theoreticians in a rush to publish".
谁写的
Who wrote that?
匿名的
It's anonymous,
用户名为"一般相对论"
and user name "General Relativity."
我要回复
Well... I'm responding to it.
别...把自己搞得跟他们一个档次
Uh, don't lower yourself to their level.
我只是保护我们的工作成果
Look, I am simply going to defend our work,
以科学家的方式理论
scientist to scientist.
如果沟通失败的话
And failing that,
就暗示他的母亲很享受
suggest that his mother enjoys a string
与人类以及非人类爱人有一腿
of both human and non-human lovers.
谢尔顿  我的名字也在论文上
Sheldon, my name's on that paper, too.
这样做没好处
There's no upside to doing this.
他又评论了
He just left another comment.
说什么
What does it say?
"经研究  对于库霍氏的
"Upon review, I've changed my mind about
时空像超流体的假设
The Cooper-Hofstadter hypothesis
我改变了自己的看法  事实上
That space-time is like a superfluid. In fact,
这启发我有了自己的理论
It's inspired me to come up with my own theory.
也许时空就像两个
Maybe space-time is like two clowns
脑袋进了水的小丑
with their heads in a bucket,
就像库珀和霍夫斯塔德"
much like Cooper and Hofstadter."
我现在可以回复了吗
Can I respond now?
回吧
Do it.
调戏公牛  就等着被角戳
You mess with the bull, you get the horns.
我要让他知道  我的角有多硬[有多淫荡]
I'm about to show this guy just how horny I can be.
其他人来回吧
Somebody else do it.
医生  请帮我
Doctor, please help me.
我想我可能会变成杀人猩猩
I think I might be turning into a killer gorilla.
你为什么会觉得你会变成杀人猩猩
Why do you think you're turning into a killer gorilla
而不是普通猩猩呢
and not just a regular gorilla?
因为普通猩猩是吃素的
Because regular gorillas are vegetarians,
而我刚咬下了你的前台的手指
and I just bit the fingers off your receptionist!
好啦  看得够多了
Okay, we've seen plenty.
不  遥控器给我
No! Give me the remote.
小心  她会咬掉你的手指
Careful. She'll bite your fingers off.
我刚才在上网
Okay, well, I've been poking around the internet,
我想我找到了大家更想看的东西
and I think I found something we'll enjoy watching even more.
什么
What is it?
伯纳黛特参加选美的视频
Oh, just a video of Bernadette in a beauty pageant.
什么
What?!
我受到教训了
Okay, I learned my lesson.
取笑他人是不对的
Making fun of people is wrong!
我还没有接受教训
I haven't learned my lesson.
快放  快放
Play it! Play it!
大家好  我是来自加州约巴林达的
Hi. I'm Bernadette Maryann Rostenkowski
伯纳黛特·玛丽安·罗斯滕科斯基
from Yorba Linda, California.
你看起来像是会说话的纸杯蛋糕
You look like a talking cupcake!
你们应该让我
And you should pick me
当选99年加州奎兹诺斯三明治小姐  因为我要
for Miss California Quiznos 1999, because I want to...
告诉你我要什么  我真的要[辣妹组合的名曲]
Tell you what I want, what I really really want
告诉你我要什么  我真的要
I'll tell you what I want, what I really really want
我要我要我要
I wanna, I wanna, I wanna, I wanna
真滴  真滴  真滴
Really, really, really be
很想成为99年加州奎兹诺斯三明治小姐
Miss California Quiznos 1999!
再放一遍  再放一遍
Play it again! Play it again!
他回复了吗
Did he respond yet?
还没有
Hmm. No, not yet.
也许我们不应该和他一般见识
Well, maybe we shouldn't have sunk to his level.
也没那么糟糕吧
It wasn't that bad.
再念一遍
Read it back one more time.
"亲爱的先生  我们不是疯子也不是妄想成名
"My good sir, we are neither crackpots nor wannabes.
事实上  我们是所处领域的专家
In fact, we are experts in our fields.
你躲在匿名之后时
And while you hide behind your anonymity,
我们站在自己的论文之后
We stand behind our paper.
而且今晚稍后  也会站在你妈的身后"
And later tonight, your mother".
你不觉得太粗俗了吗
And you don't think that's too rough?
我们只是站在她身后
We're just standing behind her.
又不是说我们会突然大叫来吓她
It's not like we're gonna say "boo" and scare her.
你怎么没告诉过我们你参加过选美
How could you not tell us you were in beauty pageants?
因为太丢人了
'Cause it's embarrassing.
是的  太丢人了
It is; it truly is.
好吧
Yeah, well...
艾米以自己为主角
Amy writes Little House
写了《草原小屋》的同人小说
on the Prairie fan fiction
还发到网上了
about herself and posts it on the Internet.
不是吧
No!
为什么  我哪里得罪你了
Why? What did I do?!
抱歉  我得把注意力从我身上转移
Sorry, I had to get the spotlight off me,
攻击其他女生是我接受的选美特训内容之一
and tearing down other women is part of my pageant training.
好的  我们现在就看
Okay. We are reading that right now.
拜托别看
No, please don't.
反正今晚都丢人了  来吧
We got embarrassed tonight. Come on.
但这是隐私
But it's personal.
为什么  是写的你和谢尔顿吗
Why? Is it about you and Sheldon?
不是
No.
老天  是她和谢尔顿的事
Oh, my God, it's about her and Sheldon.
不是我和谢尔顿的事
It's not about me and Sheldon.
女主是19世纪名叫艾米莉亚的年轻女生
It's about a young woman in the 1800s named Amelia...
她爱上了穿越时空的
and the time-traveling physicist named Cooper
名叫库珀的物理学家
she falls in love with.
-拜托给我们看看  -拜托
- Please show us? - Please?
-不  -你应该知道无论怎样我们都会看的
- No. - You know I'm gonna read it either way.
希望你运气好能找到
Good luck finding it.
艾米莉亚和
Amelia and...
穿越时...
the time-trav...
找到了
Found it!
"草原的黎明刚过
"It was just past dawn on the prairie,
和其它早上一样
and like every morning,
艾米莉亚准备做家务活
Amelia prepared to do her chores.
只是今早感觉有些不同"
Except something about this morning felt different."
为什么
Why?
为什么感觉不同了
Why did it feel different?
"也许是因为空气中响过冬天的第一声低语
"Maybe it was the first whisper of winter in the air,
也许是因为她即将发现的
o maybe it was the unconscious handsome man
躺在草地上  有着瓷器一样精致的皮肤
with porcelain skin and curious clothing
以及穿着古怪衣衫的英俊男子
she was about to discover lying in the field.
这个男人将开拓她的思想至无限可能
A man who would open her mind to new possibilities
也会让她的身体领略未知的感受"
and her body to new feelings."
曾经我很孤独  没有朋友
You know, there was a time when I was alone and had no friends.
我开始想念那种时光了
I'm starting to miss that.
他还是没回复
He still hasn't responded.
他怎么这么慢
What's taking him so long?
你真的想要他回复吗
Do you really want him to write back?
是的  无论他回复什么
Yeah, I do. No matter how he responds,
我都打算用一只一脸不屑的猫
I am going to destroy him with a picture of a bored cat
说"哦  真的喵"的图来羞辱他
saying, "Oh, really?"
干得喵
Me-wow.
你做什么
What are you doing?
我注册了一些小号
I've, uh, created some other user accounts
这样可以赞美他们的论文
so I can post positive comments about their paper.
"这小孩家家的理论
"This wee li'l bairn of a theory
差点惊到我苏格兰短裙掉了"
nearly blew my kilt off"?
不  你应该像爱丁堡大学的
No. You have to read it how Dr. Angus McDoogal
安格斯·麦克多戈尔博士那样读
of the University of Edinburgh would.
"这小孩家家的理论
"This wee li'l bairn of a theory
差点惊到我苏格兰短裙掉了"
nearly blew me kilt off."
他回复了
He wrote back!
"库霍氏求助于幼稚的玩笑话
"Cooper and Hofstadter resorting to juvenile attempts at humor
证明了他们没有可支持他们可笑论文的东西"
Is proof they have nothing to back up their ridiculous paper.
这一点也不奇怪
It should come as no surprise
考虑到他们所在的加州理工  本质上是技术学院
Given they work at Cal Tech, essentially a technical school,
那里的物理学家从根本上来说就只是工程师"
where even the physicists are basically engineers."
"工程师"
"Engineers"!
知道这有多侮辱人吗
Do you know how insulting that is?
知道
Yes.
各位  这家伙只是想尽办法
Guys, this person's just going out of their way
来激怒你们
to get a rise out of you.
没错  但还是气死人
Yeah, but it's still so aggravating.
其它的评论都是正面的溢美之词
Yeah, well, all the other comments said really nice things.
-看那些就行了  -没错
- Focus on those. - Yeah.
莫斯科大学的迪米崔·普兰克维克博士说
Dr. Dmitri Plancovik of Moscow University said,
"论文赞赞哒
"Dis paper great.
入口柔  一线喉  劲过伏特加"
I love it more than 'wodka.".
懂吗  配上口音才有感觉
See? Better with the accent.
然后...发送
And... send.
你写的什么
What did you write?
我受够了躲避恶霸的日子
I'm done hiding from bullies.
我要在现实生活中勇敢面对
I'm taking this into the real world.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
我告诉他  我愿意在任何时间
I told him we'll meet him face-to-face
任何地点  跟他见面
anytime, anywhere.
你疯了吗  你都不认识这个人
Are you crazy? You don't know who this person is.
-快删掉  -快点  谢尔顿
- Delete that! - Come on, Sheldon!
好啦  好啦  冷静
Oh, okay, okay, calm down.
是他
It's him!
他想视频聊天
He's trying to video chat.
也许我不应该把事惹到现实生活中来
Perhaps I shouldn't have taken this into the real world.
哦  真的喵
Oh, really?
'"时间旅行"我不理解'  艾米莉亚说
'"Time travel? I don't understand,' "Said Amelia.
库珀盯着她说
Cooper stared at her.
'哪部分你不理解  "时间"还是"旅行"'
'Which rd don't you understand, time or travel?'"
连你幻想里的谢尔顿都这么让人心塞
Wow, even in your fantasies Sheldon's kind of exhausting.
他是在开头才这样
He's like that in the beginning,
方便她来改变他
so she can change him.
这叫写作功力
It's called good writing.
也叫有梦最美
And wishful thinking.
"艾米莉亚非常受伤"
"It stung Amelia "
在她听到他用那种方式说话时
When he spoke to her this way.
"在她那间小小的学校中
In her little one-room schoolhouse,
她一直是最聪明的学生
she was always the smartest student,
常常傲视班里被她击败的男生们
regularly besting the boys in her class,
但眼前的人  并不是男生
but this was no boy in front of her--
而是一个男人"
"This was a man.
好戏来了
Here we go.
"库珀给艾米莉亚
"Cooper told Amelia
讲了许多未来可以拥有的
about all the strange and incredible things
陌生而又神奇的东西  比如电脑
the future would hold, like computers
还有可以活过30岁
and living past 30.
他问她有没有什么问题要问
He asked her if she had any questions.
她只渴望听到一个问题的答案
All she longed to ask was
就是他的心是否和自己一样跳得飞快
if his heart was beating as fast as hers,
但她又害怕听到答案"
but she was too afraid to hear the answer."
艾米莉亚真可怜
Oh, Amelia.
"取而代之  她问的是
"So instead she asked if, in the future,
在未来  蒙大拿有没有成为一个州"
montana ever became a state."
在十九世纪这就算调情了
In the 1800s that was considered flirting.
我受够了人们在网上总是那么毒舌
I'm so sick of people being mean on the Internet.
我觉得匿名使得人们以为
Well, I think the anonymity makes everyone feel like
可以乱说那些当面说不出口的话了
they can say things they'd never say to your face.
有意思
Interesting.
我想不出有什么话
I can't think of a single thing
是我不能当面说出口的
I wouldn't say to someone's face.
这点我们还真"没注意到"呢
Never noticed that about you.
知道吗  至少你们做出了成果
You know what? A-At least you guys did something.
你们想到了这个理论
You know, you-you had a theory,
写出了论文
you wrote a paper,
切切实实地作出了贡献
you made an actual contribution.
做那种的事的人只会对别人的作品指指点点
All guys like this do is just stand on other people's work.
他说得对
He's right.
要不我们给他打回去
I say we call this person back.
我们又用不着躲躲藏藏的
We've got no reason to hide.
没错  去吧  打给他
All right, do it. Call him.
看看这个傻逼有过什么成就
Let's find out what this loser's ever accomplished.
和我一起点击
Click it with me.
一  二  三...
One, two, three...
-点  -击
- Click. - Click.
哎呦  你们好啊
Well, hello there.
霍金教授
Professor Hawking?
哥们儿  照镜子瞅瞅你那什么表情啊
Oh, brother, you should see the look on your faces.
你真不喜欢我们的论文吗
You really didn't like our paper?
我非常喜欢你们的论文
I like your paper very much.
这个假设很有趣
The premise is intriguing.
那你为什么还要攻击我们
Then why are you attacking us?
如果你在椅子里被困了四十年
If you were sitting in a chair for 40 years,
你也会觉得无聊的
you'd get bored, too.
总之
Anyway,
我得走了
got to go.
答应给邻居家小孩补数学课
I promised to help the neighbor kid with his math homework.
回见
Ciao.
史蒂芬·霍金喜欢我们的论文
Stephen Hawking liked our paper.
说这个假设很有趣
Said the premise is intriguing.
再见到你很高兴
Good to see you again,
史蒂芬·霍金喜欢我们的论文先生
Mr. Stephen-Hawking-Liked-Our-Paper.
彼此彼此  我们的假设很有趣先生
And you as well, Mr. Our-Premise-Is-Intriguing.
你好啊  我承认这事儿挺酷先生
How do you do, Mr. I'll- Admit-That's-Pretty-Cool?
好  你一直故意下套害我像白痴
Yeah, you keep setting me up for failure.
"带着沉重的心情
"With a heavy heart,
艾米莉亚站在刚修好的时间机器前
Amelia stood before the newly repaired time machine.
她后悔把库珀需要的部分给他了
She regretted giving Cooper the part he needed."
因为她想的是他能交出她需要的那"部分"
Because she wanted him to give her the part she needed.
-行了  够了  -怎么了
- Okay, that's enough. - What?
不要啊  我真的很想知道后来怎么了...
No! I really want to know what happens--
还有伯纳黛特
and Bernadette
真滴  真滴  真滴想知道  后来怎么了嘛
really, really, really wants to know what happens.
你们就是在拿我取乐
You're just making fun of me.
我刚刚是在开玩笑的  抱歉
I was just kidding. I'm sorry.
这个故事写得真的很好
And the story's really good!
就是啊  他有没有留下
No, it is! Does he stay?
他们接吻了吗  她最后知道蒙大拿的事了吗
Do they kiss? Does she find out about Montana?
拜托
Please?
好吧
Fine.
"在库珀准备起飞时
"As Cooper prepared to depart,
泪水溢满了艾米莉亚的眼睛
Tears filled Amelia's eyes.
他拉起她的手说'我不能留下来
he took her hand in his and said, 'I can't stay,
但我永远都不会忘记你的'
but I will never forget you.'
他的手指轻轻抚过她的脸颊
He brushed his fingers against her cheek,
然后快步地走入机器
then quickly stepped into the machine.
'请不要离开'  她呢喃道
'Please don't go,' she whispered.
但一切都已经太晚了
But it was too late.
引擎呼啸着启动了"
The engine hummed to life."
但他们还没有接过吻啊
But they didn't even kiss.
"她转过身去
"She turned away,
抹掉眼中的泪水
wiping her eyes.
她无法忍受眼睁睁看着
She couldn't bear to watch
自己的一生所爱永远地消失离开
her one chance at true love disappear forever.
然后...
Then...
她感到一只强壮的手搭在自己的肩头
she felt a strong hand on her shoulder
将她扳回身去
spin her around.
是库珀"
it was Cooper."
太棒了
Yes!
"'未来怎么办'  艾米莉亚问道
"'What about the future?' asked Amelia.
他深深地注视着她的双眸  轻声说
He looked deeply into her eyes and whispered,
'没有你就没有未来'
'There is no future without you.'
他一把将她拉近
He pulled her in close.
她的身体开始颤抖
She began to tremble all over.
能感受到他温暖的呼吸..."
She felt his warm breath..."
你们肯定不信刚刚史蒂芬·霍金说什么了
You will not believe what Stephen Hawking just said.
-滚  -出去
- Get out!  - Not now!
水够热吗
Is the water warm enough?
考虑到你花时间烧柴生火
Given the fact that you took the time to build a wood fire,
从井里打水又烧热
draw the water from the well and heat it,
如果我再抱怨就太无礼了
it would be rude to complain.
但既然你都问了  有点儿冷
But since you asked, it's a little nippy.
我能解决
I can fix that.
我很难不注意到你那不同寻常的贴身衣物
I couldn't help but notice your unusual undergarments.
那不是贴身衣物
They're not undergarments.
那是小裤裤
They're Underoos.
我来的地方把这个叫做
Where I come from, they're known as
"又酷又好玩的裤"
"Underwear that's fun to wear."
那蜘蛛的意义又是什么
And what's the significance of the spider?
那代表着蜘蛛侠
Oh, that represents Spider-Man.
蜘蛛能干啥  他就能干啥
He does whatever a spider can.
未来说话都很押韵是吧
There's a lot of rhyming in the future, isn't there?
你说得对
You're right.
比我想得更诡异
This is even weirder than I thought.
要不要我停下
You want me to stop reading?
开什么玩笑  继续  继续
Are you kidding? No, no.
"他站起身来  方便她擦干身体..."
"As he stood for Amelia to dry him..."
告诉我  库珀...
So, tell me, Cooper...
未来肌肤相亲的方式也不同吗
are the ways of physical love different in the future?
够了  我听够了
Yeah, okay, I'm good.